National Visionary Leadership Project Interviews and Conference Collection AFC 2004/007
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series III: Interviews
  - Leo Branton interview conducted by Dale Mason Cochran, 2008-07-29, AFC 2004/007: 248
    - Moving Images, 10 videocassettes of 10 (Betacam SP) (300 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.003; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.004; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.005; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.006; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.007; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.008; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.009; AFC 2004/007: 248.MV.010
  - Mary T. Christian oral history interview conducted by Courtney Ward, 2007-10-19, AFC 2004/007: 249
    Mary Christian was a teacher, professor of education at Hampton University and Delegate of the Virginia House.
    The interview includes Mary Christian's memories of growing up in Hampton, Virginia, teaching at Hampton public schools and encouraging her students' involvement in the civil rights movement. She recalls the desegregation of public schools, serving on the school board and earning her Ph. D. She discusses her career teaching at Hampton University, her involvement in local politics and her election to the Virginia House of Delegates.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655171
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (120 pages) (Box-folder 21/268)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; 1 videocassette of 1 (DVCam) (184 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 249.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 249.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 249.MV.003
  - Moses Cobb oral history interview conducted by Mary Brooks, 2007-12-01, AFC 2004/007: 250
    Moses Cobb was a janitor and skycap for American Airlines.
    The interview includes Moses Cobb's memories of growing up in Athens, Georgia, moving to Baltimore, Maryland and working as an airport janitor. He recalls his career as a skycap with American Airlines and serving in the army. He discusses his involvement at his church and offers advice for young African Americans.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655172
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (19 pages) (Box-folder 21/269)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 250.MV.001
  - Vernon Coffey oral history interview conducted by Tiffany Tucker, 2007, AFC 2004/007: 251
    Vernon Coffey was a Lieutenant Colonel in the army and a corporate executive.
    The interview includes Vernon Coffey's memories of growing up in Kansas City, Kansas, working as a train waiter and joining in the army. He recalls attending Officer Candidate School, serving in the Korean War, and becoming a paratrooper. He discusses the Vietnam War, serving as an army aid to the President, and his work as a corporate executive for General Mills and several other companies.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655173
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (65 pages) (Box-folder 21/270)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 251.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 251.MV.002
  - Maria Cole oral history interview conducted by Camille O. Cosby, 2009-02-05, AFC 2004/007: 252
    Maria Cole was a jazz singer and the wife of Nat King Cole.
    The interview includes Maria Cole's memories of growing up in Massachusetts and attending the Palmer Memorial Institute founded by her aunt, Charlotte Hawkins Brown. She recalls singing as a child and starting her career as a jazz vocalist as a teenager performing with Duke Ellington. She discusses meeting Nat King Cole, their marriage and facing discrimination in housing, the entertainment world and public accommodations.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655174
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (129 pages) (Box-folder 21/271)
    - Graphic Images, 5 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/499)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (DVCam) (124 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 252.MV.001
  - Calvin Coleman oral history interview conducted by Steven M. Page, 2007-09-29, AFC 2004/007: 253
    Calvin Coleman was a mechanic, bus driver and trainer for Capital Transit in Washington, D.C.
    The interview includes Calvin Coleman's memories of growing up in Spotsylvania, Virginia and serving in the army during World War II in Italy. He recalls moving to Washington, D.C. and his career as a mechanic, bus driver and trainer for the Capital Transit Company. He discusses the 1968 riots, becoming a deacon at the Florida Avenue Baptist Church and raising his family.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655175
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (39 pages) (Box-folder 21/272)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 253.MV.001
  - Herbert Daughtry oral history interview conducted by Christopher Smith, 2007-10-09, AFC 2004/007: 254
    Herbert Daughtry was a civil rights activist and minister with the House of the Lord denomination.
    The interview includes Herbert Daughtry's memories of growing up in Georgia, moving to Brooklyn and his family's history of ministry. He recalls his drug addiction and incarceration, founding his church in a storefront and joining the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC) and Operation Breadbasket. He discusses founding the organization National Black United Front, his work with the Atlantic Yards development in Brooklyn and his work with refugees from Darfur.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655178
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (71 pages) (Box-folder 21/273)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 254.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 254.MV.002
  - Maggie Dews oral history interview conducted by Brandon D. Jackson, 2007, AFC 2004/007: 255
    Maggie Dews was a farmer and domestic worker.
    The interview includes Maggie Dews' memories of growing up in Brownsville, Texas, marrying her husband and working as a farmer. She recalls raising her children, working as a domestic and her involvement in church.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655179
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (29 pages) (Box-folder 21/274)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 255.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 255.MV.002
  - Thornton Dial oral history interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-06-26, AFC 2004/007: 256
    Thornton Dial was a vernacular artist known for his assemblages and sculpture.
    The interview includes Thornton Dial's memories of growing up in Bessemer, Alabama, living with his grandmother and aunt and dropping out of school at age 13. He recalls working many odd jobs, his career as a machine operator and welder at Pullman-Standard and starting a furniture company with his son. He discusses his process of creating sculpture and assemblages from found objects, his friendships with artist Lonnie Holley and art collector Bill Arnett, and his major exhibitions.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655180
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (127 pages) (Box-folder 21/275)
    - Graphic Images, 30 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/500)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (DVCam) (192 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 256.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 256.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 256.MV.003
  - Joyce Dixon oral history interview conducted by Eryn V. Reid, 2007-10-18, AFC 2004/007: 257
    Joyce Dixon was a civic leader and the founder of Creative Management Technology.
    The interview includes Joyce Dixon's memories of growing up in Greensboro, North Carolina, attending Bennett College, and marrying her husband Jacob Dixon, an air force officer. She recalls the deaths of her two children, returning to college and moving to Florida. She discusses founding Creative Management Technology with her husband, her volunteer work with Links, Inc. and fundraising for Bennett College.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655181
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (51 pages) (Box-folder 21/276)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 257.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 257.MV.002
  - Roosevelt Dorn oral history interview conducted by Krystle A. Evans, 2007-11-07, AFC 2004/007: 258
    Roosevelt Dorn was the mayor of Inglewood, California.
    The interview includes Roosevelt Dorn's memories of growing up in Checotah, Oklahoma, serving in the air force and working as a bailiff while he attended law school in California. He recalls serving as a juvenile court judge and his election as mayor of Inglewood, California. He discusses his accomplishments as mayor including bringing new development in Inglewood and lowering the crime rate.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655182
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (29 pages) (Box-folder 21/277)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 258.MV.001
  - Julian Dugas oral history interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-10-04, AFC 2004/007: 259
    Julian Dugas was a civil rights lawyer and law professor at Howard University.
    The interview includes Julian Dugas' memories of growing up in Augusta, Georgia and attending South Carolina State University and Howard University Law School. He recalls serving in the navy during World War II and working on the school desegregation case Bolling v. Sharpe and other civil rights cases. He discusses teaching law at Howard University, starting the Neighborhood Legal Services organization and working as the District of Columbia city administrator.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655183
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (103 pages) (Box-folder 21/278)
    - Graphic Images, 8 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/501)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (DVCam) (192 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 259.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 259.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 259.MV.003
  - Ovide Duncantell oral history interview conducted by Terri Mason, 2007-10-11, AFC 2004/007: 260
    Ovide Duncantell was a civic leader and founder of the Black Heritage Society.
    The interview includes Ovide Duncantell's memories of growing up in Louisiana, serving in the air force and moving to Houston, Texas. He recalls working as an insurance agent and his position with the Houston Community Action Association, an anti-poverty program. He discusses starting a free breakfast program for children, running for city council and founding the Black Heritage Society.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655184
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (63 pages) (Box-folder 21/279)
    - Graphic Images, 10 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/502)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 260.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 260.MV.002
  - Louis Farrakhan oral history interview conducted by Camille O. Cosby, 2008-05-07, AFC 2004/007: 261
    Louis Farrakhan was the head of the Nation of Islam.
    Louis Farrakhan was interviewed by Camille O. Cosby on May 7, 2008 for the National Visionary Leadership Project in Chicago, Illinois.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655238
    - Graphic Images, 15 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/503)
    - Moving Images, 4 videocassettes of 4 (DVCam) (256 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 261.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 261.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 261.MV.003; AFC 2004/007: 261.MV.004
  - Clarence Faulcon oral history interview conducted by Matthew Frazier, 2007-10-17, AFC 2004/007: 262
    Clarence Faulcon was a pianist, conductor and professor of music.
    The interview includes Clarence Faulcon's memories of growing up in Philadelphia, learning to play piano, and attending Lincoln University and the University of Pennsylvania. He recalls teaching music to junior high students, earning his Ph.D. in music and conducting the Philadelphia Concert Orchestra. He discusses teaching at Cazenovia College, performing with his wife, Jacqueline, and starting a program to showcase the works of African American composers.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655185
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (69 pages) (Box-folder 21/281)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 262.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 262.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 262.MV.003
  - Jacqueline Faulcon oral history interview conducted by Matthew Frazier, 2007-10-20, AFC 2004/007: 263
    Jacqueline Faulcon was a pianist, singer and music teacher.
    The interview includes Jacqueline Faulcon's memories of growing up in Kingston, New York, her career as a music teacher and raising her son. She discusses her work with the Musical Fund Society of Philadelphia, teaching in public schools and colleges, and performing with her husband Clarence.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655186
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (30 pages) (Box-folder 21/282)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 263.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 263.MV.002
  - Anna and Fred Franklin oral history interview conducted by Shaneka Roberts, 2007-10-17, AFC 2004/007: 264
    Fred Franklin was an air force officer and corporate manager. Anna Franklin was a school secretary and homemaker.
    The interview includes Fred Franklin's memories of growing up in Alexandria, Virginia, attending West Virginia State College and serving in the air force. Anna Franklin recalls growing up in North Carolina, moving to Alexandria, Virginia and working as a school secretary. Fred Franklin discusses his career as an air force officer, working as a manager at Control Data Corporation and owning a McDonald's franchise.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655187
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (92 pages) (Box-folder 22/283)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 264.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 264.MV.002
  - Mary Lee Bendolph oral history interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-07-31, AFC 2004/007: 265
    Mary Lee Bendolph was a member of the Gee's Bend Quilters Collective.
    The interview includes Mary Lee Bendolph's memories of growing up in Gee's Bend, Alabama, becoming a teenage mother and learning to make quilts from her mother. She recalls meeting art dealer Bill Arnett, learning more about the artistic quality of quilts and the first showing of the quilts in Houston, Texas. She discusses registering to vote during the civil rights movement, her involvement at church and raising her family.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655231
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (57 pages) (Box-folder 22/824)
    - Graphic Images, 10 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/504)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (DVCam) (128 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 265.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 265.MV.002
  - Gee's Bend Quiltmakers Mary Lee Bendolph, Lucy Mingo, Nettie Young, Essie Pettway, and China Pettway interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-07-31, AFC 2004/007: 266
    The interview includes footage of an intergenerational group of women working on a quilt together.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655240
    - Graphic Images, 4 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/505)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (DVCam) (64 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 266.MV.001
  - Nettie Young oral history interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-07-31, AFC 2004/007: 267
    Nettie Young was a sharecropper and member of the Gee's Bend Quilters Collective.
    The interview includes Nettie Young's memories of growing up in Rehoboth, Alabama, working as a sharecropper and moving to Gee's Bend. She recalls her religious conversion, making her first quilt, and joining the Freedom Quilting Bee. She discusses her involvement in the civil rights movement, meeting art dealer Bill Arnett and displaying her quilts in museums.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655232
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (57 pages) (Box-folder 22/285)
    - Graphic Images, 14 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/506)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (DVCam) (64 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 267.MV.001
  - Lucy Mingo oral history interview conducted by Johnnetta Cole, 2008-07-31, AFC 2004/007: 268
    Lucy Mingo was a cook and member of the Gee's Bend Quilters Collective.
    The interview includes Lucy Mingo's memories of growing up in Rehoboth, Alabama, raising ten children and her involvement at church. She recalls learning to sew, making her first quilt and joining the Freedom Quilting Bee. She discusses her participation in the civil rights movement, working as a school cook, meeting art dealer Bill Arnett and selling her quilts.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655301
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (60 pages) (Box-folder 22/286)
    - Graphic Images, 11 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/507)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (DVCam) (64 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 268.MV.001
  - Sam Gilliam oral history interview conducted by Maxine Baker, 2008-10-10, AFC 2004/007: 269
    Sam Gilliam was an abstract artist and member of the Washington Color School.
    The interview includes Sam Gilliam's memories of growing up in Tupelo, Mississippi and Louisville, Kentucky and attending the University of Louisville where he majored in art. He recalls serving in the army, teaching art in public schools and moving to Washington, D.C. He discusses the Washington Color School, his success in New York and his methods for creating art.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655188
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (122 pages) (Box-folder 22/287)
    - Graphic Images, 13 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/508)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (DVCam) (192 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 269.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 269.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 269.MV.003
  - Ulysses S. Griggs oral history interview conducted by Jessica E. Kellog, 2007-10-17, AFC 2004/007: 270
    Ulysses S. Griggs was a social worker and civic leader.
    The interview includes Ulysses S. Griggs' memories of growing up in California, attending the University of California, Los Angeles and serving in the army. He recalls his career as a disability advocate with Community Rehabilitation Services, volunteering at Children's Hospital and donating blood. He discusses raising his daughters and his service with Kappa Alpha Psi.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655189
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (46 pages) (Box-folder 22/288)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 270.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 270.MV.002
  - Grace Hampton oral history interview conducted by Wanda Timms, 2007-10-22, AFC 2004/007: 271
    Grace Hampton was an artist, professor and assistant director of the National Endowment for the Arts.
    The interview includes Grace Hampton's memories of growing up in Alabama and Chicago, Illinois, taking art classes and attending the School of the Art Institute of Chicago. She recalls teaching at elementary schools and the Southside Community Art Center and developing her specialty in African art. She discusses earning her Ph.D. at Arizona State University, teaching at several universities and her position at the National Endowment for the Arts.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655190
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (78 pages) (Box-folder 22/289)
    - Graphic Images, 5 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 32/509)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 271.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 271.MV.002
  - Gertrude Jeannette oral history interview conducted by Patrick Senat, 2007-10-16, AFC 2004/007: 272
    Gertrude Jeannette was an actress, director and the founder of the H.A.D.L.E.Y. Players.
    The interview includes Gertrude Jeannette's memories of growing up in Arkansas, meeting her husband, boxer Joe Jeannette, and moving to New York. She recalls becoming the first female cab driver in New York, acting with the American Negro Theater and on Broadway, and writing plays. She discusses founding the H.A.D.L.E.Y. Players, the Harlem theater community and arts funding.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655191
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (51 pages) (Box-folder 22/290)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 272.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 272.MV.002
  - Tobe Johnson oral history interview conducted by Derrick Johnson, 2007, AFC 2004/007: 273
    The interview includes Tobe Johnson's memories of growing up in Birmingham, Alabama, attending Morehouse College and earning his Ph.D. in political science at Columbia University. He discusses his marriage, his career as a professor at Morehouse College, and the influence of Morehouse students on the civil rights movement.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655196
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (34 pages) (Box-folder 22/291)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 273.MV.001
  - Kenneth Lavon Johnson oral history interview conducted by Ruth Mathenge, 2007-10-12, AFC 2004/007: 274
    Kenneth Lavon Johnson was a civil rights lawyer and district court judge.
    The interview includes Kenneth Lavon Johnson's memories of growing up in Mississippi, attending Southern University and participating in restaurant sit-ins. He recalls attending Howard University Law School and serving in the army during the Korean War as a JAG officer. He discusses his career at the Department of Justice, where he served as a lawyer in the South for many civil rights cases, and becoming a district court judge in Baltimore, Maryland.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655194
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (95 pages) (Box-folder 22/292)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 274.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 274.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 274.MV.003
  - Colonel Stone Johnson oral history interview conducted by Kintisha Matthews, 2007-10-07, AFC 2004/007: 275
    Colonel Stone Johnson was a railroad clerk, union leader and civil rights activist.
    The interview includes Colonel Stone Johnson's memories of growing up in Birmingham, Alabama, working as a railroad clerk and as a union representative for the Brotherhood of Railway Clerks. He recalls labor disputes, his involvement in the civil rights movement in Alabama, and joining the Southern Christian Leadership Coalition (SCLC). He discusses serving as Rev. Fred Shuttlesworth's bodyguard, facing harassment and violence, and the bombing of the Bethel Baptist Church.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655195
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (58 pages) (Box-folder 22/293)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 275.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 275.MV.002
  - Clarence B. Jones oral history interview conducted by Renee Poussaint, 2008-03-26, AFC 2004/007: 276
    Clarence B. Jones was a lawyer who defended Martin Luther King, Jr.